A Guide to the Norfolk & Western Railway Company Construction Site Photographs, 1967-1981, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Norfolk & Western Railway Company Construction Site Photographs, 1967-1981, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1997-027
0.6 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The collection includes approximately 360 photographs (and in some cases, photocopies of photographs) of railroad construction in Southwest Virginia. The majority of images date from 1967-1981. There is also a folder of undated images.
Norfolk and Western Railway Company.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Norfolk & Western Railway Company Construction Site Photographs were purchased by Special Collections in 1997.
Historical Note
The Norfolk & Western Railway was established through a reorganization of the bankrupt Norfolk and Western Railroad in 1896, the latter company itself having arisen from the Atlantic, Mississippi & Ohio Railroad, a successor to the Norfolk and Petersburg Railroad. In order to raise capital to pay off debt, meet its payroll and other obligations, and make continued improvements to the line, the new company issued $23 million in preferred stock, $66 million in common stock, and $62.5 million gold bonds paying four percent, secured through a consolidated mortgage to the Mercantile Trust Company of New York.
Through expansion and various mergers, the N&W grew to become a major U.S. carrier, serving 14 states. The company manufactured steam locomotives at its own Roanoke Machine Works (established in Roanoke, Virginia in 1882), and among the railroad's affiliated holdings were several hotels. In 1982, the N&W combined with the Southern Railway to form Norfolk Southern Corporation.
Scope and Content
The collection includes approximately 360 photographs (and in some cases, photocopies of photographs) of railroad construction in Southwest Virginia. The majority of images date from 1967-1981. There is also a folder of undated images.
Arrangement
The photographs are organized in chronological order.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Special Collections includes many other collections relating to railroad history in this region, as well as Norfolk & Western Railway, Norfolk & Western Railroad, and various subsidiaries. You can browse and search within a list of these collections online through Virginia Heritage.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Norfolk and Western Railway Company.
Genre and Form Terms:
Photographs
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Railroad
Contents List
- July 7, 1967 (Box-folder 2-1)
- August 1, 1967 (Box-folder 2-2)
- September 21, 1967 (Box-folder 2-3)
- November 3, 1967 (Box-folder 2-4)
- May 3, 1968 (Box-folder 2-5)
- July 27, 1968 (Box-folder 2-6)
- April 29, 1969 (Box-folder 2-7)
- April 30, 1969 (Box-folder 2-8)
- August 26, 1969 (Box-folder 2-9)
- October 12, 1978 (Box-folder 2-10)
- December 19, 1978 (Box-folder 1-1)
- August 6, 1979 (Box-folder 1-2)
- December 11, 1979 (Box-folder 1-3)
- May 1980 (Box-folder 1-4)
- June 1980 (Box-folder 1-5)
- July 1980 (Box-folder 1-6)
- August 1980 (Box-folder 1-7)
- August 3, 1980 (Box-folder 1-8)
- August 9, 1980 (Box-folder 1-9)
- November-December 1980 (Box-folder 1-10)
- February 1981 (Box-folder 1-11)
- April 13, 1981 (Box-folder 1-12)
- April 15-May 19, 1981 (Box-folder 1-13)
- April 28, 1981 (Box-folder 1-14)
- May 6, 1981 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Undated photographs (Box-folder 1-6)